I wish I'd never been born.
（ペコ）
生まれてこなければ よかった
スコンクで負けた
I got skunked.
The whole world's laughing at me.
今頃 世界中の笑い者だ
（オババ）あのさあ
悪いけど今日 帰っとくれよ ペコ
Peco, do me a favor and go home.
You're making it hard to breathe in here.
空気 よどむ
見えないよ
I can't see his weaknesses.
どこにある？ やつの隙
Where are they?
Hoshino Yutaka (Peco)
Right-Handed Penhold
Racket: Soft Front
Style: Offensive, Close to Table
Hoshino Yutaka (Peco)
Right-Handed Penhold
Racket: Soft Front
Style: Offensive, Close to Table
Hook loop!
Inside out loop!
Smash!
Backhand!
Inside out!
Forehand!
Oh, wow.
わあ すげえな
あれって
球種もコースも指定されてんだろ？
He's hitting predetermined shots to predetermined spots, right?
He hasn't played against any of us even once.
俺らと
１回も打ってくんないからな
He must think we suck or something.
（部員）
ナメられてんのよ 俺ら
Inside out!
Anyway, is Kong's rubber that
one you can only get in China?
（部員）
ところでコンのラバーって
国外不出の中国産ってやつ？
Probably not, since he doesn't
represent his province anymore.
（部員）
もう省の代表じゃねえから
違(ちげ)えんじゃね？
Shut up! You're distracting me!
Kong can't focus. Could you keep it down a bit?
（コーチ）ああ コンが
集中できないので 少し静かに
ああ… す… すみません
S-Sorry.
What's wrong, Wenge?
Is the chopper with glasses out today too?
君たち知らないか？
カットマンでメガネの子
Do you guys know a chopper with glasses?
ああ いますよ
Oh, yeah.
郷田(ごうだ)！ コンさん 呼んでる！
Gouda! Kong's calling for you.
Let's keep going, Coach.
（中国語の
チャイナの声）
Where is he?
Kong Wenge
Right-Handed
Chinese Penhold
Racket: Double
Reverse Soft
Style: Offensive Drive
Kong Wenge
Right-Handed
Chinese Penhold
Racket: Double
Reverse Soft
Style: Offensive Drive
（スマイルの声）
ここは静かで安全だ
It's safe and quiet here.
I really feel at ease.
とても落ち着く
大丈夫　僕はここで平気なんだ
It's okay.
I'm fine here.
僕は ここにいたいんだ
This is where I want to be.
I'll hold my breath and be quiet, like a robot.
息も殺して静かに
ロボットみたいに
So...
だから…
So leave me alone!
だから放っておいて
You're
wrong,
Smile
You're
wrong,
Smile
Blood tastes
like iron
There's hot blood
flowing in your veins
Come on
When you're in a
pinch, say it thrice
Enter the hero
Do that and I'll be there
Look for him yourself.
（スマイル）
自分で捜せばいいじゃないですか
ペコなら 多分
駅前の卓球場ですよ
Peco's probably at the table tennis hall near Odakyuu Station.
I'll draw you a map. You go.
地図 描きますから
自分で行ってくださいね
If you keep talkin' like that,
I'm seriously gonna haze you!
（大田(おおた)）そういうこと
言ってっとね 月本(つきもと)
本当に いじめるよ
でも 理屈から言えば…
But logically speaking—
Screw logic!
理屈から言うな！
（高村(たかむら)）そうじゃ！
それが体育会のおきてじゃ
Yeah, that's the iron-clad rule of sports clubs.
（小泉(こいずみ)）行くな ミスター月本
Don't go.
Mr. Tsukimoto, don't go to Tamura anymore.
君 もうタムラに行くな
Don't play against Hoshino.
星野(ほしの)とは打つな
理由が分かりません
I don't understand why I shouldn't.
ああ そうな
Yeah, me neither.
君 抜いて打つもん
星野が相手だとさ
Because you hold back when you play Hoshino.
抜きませんよ
No, I don't.
You don't even realize you're doing it, I see.
ないのね 自覚
Mr. Tsukimoto, starting tomorrow, you'll
be training with me every morning at five.
ミスター月本は あしたから
毎朝５時に私とトレーニング
You lack a thirst to win, and we're going to fix that
weak point by the time the Interhigh comes around.
勝負への執念に欠けるという
ウイークポイントを—
インハイまでに克服します
Let's get sport-spirited!
レッツ スポ根！
That's my proposal.
私 プロポーズしてますよ
それでは明朝の５時
楽しみにしてるよ
I'm looking forward to seeing you at
five tomorrow morning, Mr. Tsukimoto.
ミスター月本
（スマイル）
来ませんよ 僕 ５時なんて
I'm not coming in at 5 AM.
No problem.
（小泉）ノープロブレム
ミーは尽くすタイプだっちゃ
I'm the devoted-husband type.
Devoted! Isn't that nice, Tsukimoto?
（山田(やまだ)）尽くすってよ
よかったな 月本
末永く お幸せにな
May you live happily ever after.
A new age has dawned, and still I can't make a decision
My path is too straight for my taste, but I'll walk it
I can't choose just yet
I have to think about it
I have no idea what I want to do
I'm going crazy!
Comparing yourself to others just makes you depressed
You're alone in this world
You're always alone here
Still you're gonna do it, right?
Maybe there's nothing that only I can do
But there's no way that I
But there's no way that I won't try to leave my mark
I just want to have my fun, whatever the times
（ペコ）
炭酸も軟弱になったもんだね
Man, soft drinks are getting weaker.
健康ブームだか
何だか知らんが—
I don't know if it's some health fad or what,
but I can't stand this lightly carbonated stuff.
この微炭酸ちゅうのだけは どうも
よう スマイル
終わったんか 部活
Hey, Smile. Is practice over?
Yeah.
外周 やらされただろ
俺 サボったかんよ
I bet they made you do laps
outside because I played hooky.
Yeah.
（ペコ）お前も大変だな
Sucks to be you, getting harassed by the upperclassmen whenever I skip.
俺が休むたんびに
先輩に絡まれてよ
Yeah.
まあ それも今日までだ
Well, that ends today.
I'm giving up on table tennis.
俺 卓球 やめっから
Okay.
"Okay"? That's all?!
うんって お前ねえ…
If you don't want to play, you should quit.
イヤなら やめたらいい
無理して続けることないよ
No reason to force yourself to keep going.
（ペコ）
うん 無理して続けることないな
Yeah. No reason to force myself.
あと どんくらいある？
インハイの予選まで
How long until the Interhigh prelims?
２か月
Two months.
Good grief. Doesn't even give me time to sulk.
やれやれ
落ち込む暇もねえのかい
Old lady, I'm gonna use Table Four.
オババ ４番 借りるね
You'll have to pay.
銭はもらうよ
Today's the fourth day I've done radio
exercises in the gym all by my lonesome.
（小泉）今日で４日目だ
私は１人寂しく
体育館でラジオ体操をしている
Why won't you come to morning practice, Mr. Tsukimoto?
なぜ 君は朝練に来てくれない
ミスター月本
Why do I have to, Mr. Koizumi?
なぜ 行かなくては
いけないのですか？
ミスター小泉
A coach's job only has meaning
when he has an athlete to guide.
コーチの仕事というのはね
指導する選手が存在して
初めて成り立つの
Do you understand that you're my athlete?
君 私の選手としての自覚
ありますか？
No.
ないです
Well, I want you to think of nothing but table tennis.
君には とにかく
卓球のことだけ考えてほしい
What are you thinking about now?
今 何 考えてる？
Question five.
５問目です
Nonsense!
ナンセンス！
高校の英語教育が何の役に立つ！
What good will high school English lessons ever do you?
Be quiet, Teach! We can't concentrate!
うるへー 先生！ 気ぃ散る！
Sorry, sorry.
（小泉）ソーリー ソーリー！
English Test
until 40 after
I'm just passing the time.
（スマイル）暇つぶしなんです
Table tennis and learning English vocabulary are just ways to pass the time until I die.
卓球も英単語 覚えるのも
どうせ死ぬまでの
暇つぶしですから
（ペコ）スマイルは
ピーナッツ派？ キャラメル派？
Smile, are you a peanut man or a caramel man?
Caramel
Choco Balls
（ペコ）どっち？
（スマイル）うーん キャラメル
Caramel.
だろ？ これって常識な？
Right? It's just common sense!
But the convenience store in my
neighborhood only sells the peanut kind.
ところが近所のコンビニ
ピーナッツっきゃ置いてねえの
That crunchy stuff is just wrong.
パチパチとか邪道じゃん
やんなっちゃう
Makes me sick.
ミスター月本　何 食べてる？
Mr. Tsukimoto, what are you eating?
A hambargar.
ハンバーガーっしょ
ノット “バーガー”
Not "bargar." Burger.
“burger”
Vurger?
“burger”？
（小泉）粗悪な油を使った
コレステロールの塊だ
That's a lump of cholesterol, made of low-grade oil.
わお！
Wow!
（小泉）
今日から君の昼食は私が作る
Starting today, I'll make your lunch for you.
I'll feed you healthy meals so you can build a table tennis body.
卓球をやるための体を作る
健康食だ
I don't want—
僕 こういうの…
愛ね
It's love!
イエース！ 愛！
Yes! Love!
You look like you're having fun.
楽しそうですな
フフフ　この老いぼれにも
春がやってまいりました
Spring has finally come for this old fool.
Spring
Koizumi Jou
72 Years Old
Virgo
Koizumi Jou
72 Years Old
Virgo
何 何？ 恋文かね？
Oh, is that a love letter?
Let's aim for the top together.    Sincerely yours
Pull ups
Two-handed curls
Two-handed presses
Full squats
Shift ups
Do these every morning.
From, Koizumi Jou
To: Mr. Tsukimoto
3 sets of 20 reps
2 sets of 30 reps
3 sets of 50 reps
4 sets of 30 reps
That's some tough love.
ハードラブ
Throw it away.
捨てといて
変化つけて！
More variation!
もっと粘れ 粘れ！
動かせ 足を！
Stick with it!
Move your feet!
小泉って 力入ると
こんな感じっすか？
Is Koizumi always like this when he gets going?
いや 春だしよ
盛りついたんじゃねえの？
No. Maybe he's in heat? It is springtime.
単調なんだ
変化 もっとつけて！
You're being repetitive!
You need more variation!
Smile really hates being yelled at, though.
しかしスマイル
怒鳴(どな)られんの ウルトラ嫌うかんな
ノータッチで抜かれるな！
Don't let him ace you!
なぜ攻めない！
Why aren't you attacking?!
Don't just wait for mistakes!
ミスを待つな！
いくんだ そこで！
You should've gone for it there!
何度 言わせる！
やる気あるのか？
How many times must I say it?!
Do you even want to win?!
Where are you going, Mr. Tsukimoto? Hey!
どこへ行く ミスター月本
おい！
He fled.
（大田）逃げた
（小泉）ウェイト！ ウェイト！
Wait! Wait!
しょうがねえなあ
Hey, mister!
Oh well.
（ペコ）おお！
今日は富士山が よく見えるぜ
You can see Mt. Fuji in all its glory today.
元気出せ スマイル
いい天気だぜ
Cheer up, Smile.
The weather's great.
（スマイルの声）
何だか最近 疲れるよ
人間関係とか
Interacting with people just exhausts me lately.
卓球にしても どんどん複雑に
単純じゃなくなってくる
And table tennis is getting more complicated too.
He may be a little hard on you,
（ペコ）ちっと おめえには
厳しすぎっけど—
小泉のコーチングは
的を得てんと思うよ
but I think Koizumi's coaching is right on the money.
You're wrong, Peco.
違うんだ ペコ
I'm only in it for a good time.
僕は楽しければいい
面白ければ十分
Having fun is enough.
I don't want to sacrifice anything or drag anyone down just to win.
勝つために
何かを犠牲にしたり—
引きずり下ろしたりしたくないんだ
Shall we?
うちらもやるか
Hello!
自分は海王(かいおう)学園２年
風間竜一(かざまりゅういち)であります
I'm a second-year from Kaiou Academy, Kazama Ryuuichi!
本日は練習を
見学させていただきにまいりました
I've come today to watch you practice!
Kazama Ryuuichi
Right-Handed
Shakehand
Style: Drive Master
All-rounder
Kazama Ryuuichi
Right-Handed
Shakehand
Style: Drive Master
All-rounder
海王…
Kai-ou.
（球を打ち合う音）
（部員）なんでドラゴンが？
What's the Dragon doing here?
（部員）
昨年のインターハイ王者だぜ
He won the Interhigh last year.
（部員）
世界ジュニアでも４位じゃね？
Didn't he place fourth in the World Juniors?
（部員）なんで また片瀬(かたせ)に？
What's he doing at Katase?
Is he here scouting?
（部員）引き抜きか？
（部員）星野？
（部員）俺じゃねえか？
Hoshino?
Bet it's for me.
（部員）聞いてねえし
Nobody asked you.
（部員）しかし あの面構えで
ホントに同じ高校生かね
But with a face like that, is he really a high school student?
（小泉）少し外へ出ないか？
ミスター風間
Why don't we step outside, Mr. Kazama?
My students are all wimps.
うちの選手は気が小さいのでね
今日は月本いないよ
Tsukimoto's not here today.
お目当ては彼だろう？
He's the one you're interested in, correct?
（ドラゴン）
彼を見たのは 中学最後の県大会
I first saw him at my last middle-school prefectural tournament.
He lost, but his control, speed,
playmaking, reflexes, concentration—
その試合 彼は負けましたが—
コントロール　スピード
ゲームメイク
反射神経　集中力
すべてにおいて
中学生離れしており—
They were all far above the abilities of a middle schooler.
Honestly, I felt he was a threat.
正直 自分が脅威に感じたほどです
And yet he lost.
でも 負けた
相手は？
Who was he playing?
Sakuma Manabu.
（ドラゴン）佐久間(さくま) 学(まなぶ)
今は うちの１年ですが—
He's one of our first-years now, but I heard he used
to frequent the same table tennis hall as Tsukimoto.
以前は月本君と同じ卓球道場に
通っていたと聞いています
（小泉）なるほど
I see.
（ドラゴン）
人間の反応時間の限界は0.1秒
Human reaction time maxes out at 0.1 seconds.
You reach the acme of table tennis by getting as close to that as possible.
そこへ可能なかぎり近づくことで
卓球の極致に至る
The chairman of Kaiou Academy once said that.
（小泉）海王 理事長の言葉だ
（ドラゴン）はい 浴衣を着て
行うタイプのものとは—
Yes.
It's fundamentally different from the
"table tennis" on a hot springs vacation.
本質が違います
Was that a dig against our school?
それ うちのこと言ってる？
You're saying we're a bad fit for Tsukimoto.
つまり 君は 月本が
この学校に不釣り合いだと…
To me, he looks like a swan among ducklings here.
（ドラゴン）
自分の目には
鶏群の一鶴(いっかく)に映ります
ミスター風間にクエスチョン
Question for you, Mr. Kazama.
What are the odds of Tsukimoto beating you in
the Interhigh preliminaries in two months' time?
２か月後のインターハイ予選で—
うちの月本が君に勝つ確率
どれくらいある？
Nil.
皆無です
この星の１等賞になりたいの 俺は
I want to be No. 1 on the whole planet, you feel me?
I want to be the world champion!
世界チャンプ目指してんだな
これが
夢なの 俺の
It's my dream!
これ お前とは違うな
We're different that way, yeah?
Yeah.
In my case, it's pretty simple.
単純なのよ 俺の場合(ばやい)
ひとさまが どうなろうが
敗北なんか楽しめねえかんよ
I don't care about anyone else. I just don't find losing fun.
とにかく 勝ちゃいいかんね
Anyway, all's good as long as I win.
（スマイル）それ カッコいいね
That's pretty cool.
I'm cheering you on, Peco.
応援するよ ペコ
Then come to the club tomorrow.
ほんなら
あしたも部活 来いよな
Practice is pointless without you there.
おめえ いねえと練習なんねえ
I can feel another hot summer's coming.
（ペコ）また夏い暑が来るぜ
Smile's a Robot
何度も聞きますが—
As I've asked before: why do I have a different training regimen from everyone else?
どうして
僕だけ違うメニューなんですか？
Because you yourself are different from the others.
君が 他と違う
選手だからだよ
Let's hurry, honey.
急ごう ハニー
我々には時間がない
We don't have time to dilly-dally.
They're training with two tables.
２台練習…
しごきだぜ
Looks tough.
（小泉）遅い 遅い 遅いよ！
Too slow! Too slow! Too slow!
もっと速く！
Speed it up!
止まらない！ 動いて！
No pauses!
Keep moving!
The old man's giving him tricky ones.
厳しいとこ出すなあ ご老体
スマイルも よく拾ってんなあ
I'm impressed Smile can return them.
あいつ マラソン
すげえ速いんすよ
He runs a wicked fast marathon, you know.
Where'd you get that lollipop during practice?
お前 練習中に
そのアメ どうしたんだよ
飛びつく！ そら！
Crossover!
There! Go!
ほら！
The convenience store.
コンビニ
Too slow!
遅い！
No lying down, Tsukimoto!
寝ないの 月本！
布団ないでしょ？
There's no bed down there!
What is this going to accomplish?
こんなことして どうなるんですか
You'll get stronger.
強くなる！
That's stupid.
くだらない
Not at all.
くだるよ
Are awards and trophies really so important?
賞状やトロフィーが
そんなに大切ですか？
There are sights you can only see from the top.
頂上に立たねば
見えない風景がある
I'm not interested.
僕は興味ないです
君は そうやって
すぐ自分の殻に閉じこもる
You always withdraw into your shell like that.
That's how I live.
僕の生き方です
It's no business of yours.
先生には関係ない
Then I challenge you to a match, Mr. Tsukimoto.
ならば 試合を申し込むよ
ミスター月本
If you win, I promise never to interfere with you again.
もし 君が勝ったら—
私は今後一切
君を干渉しないことを約束する
What if I lose?
（スマイル）負けたら？
You'll be my dog.
（小泉）私の犬になってくれ
Woof, woof, woof.
ワン ワン ワン
Koizumi Jou
Right-Handed Penhold
Racket: Soft Front
72 Years Old
Koizumi Jou
Right-Handed Penhold
Racket: Soft Front
72 Years Old
You'll obey my every command.
絶対服従だよ
Makoto Tsukimoto
Right-Handed
Shakehand
Racket: Double
Reverse Soft
16 Years Old
Makoto Tsukimoto
Right-Handed
Shakehand
Racket: Double
Reverse Soft
16 Years Old
The best of three will now begin!
ベストオブスリー 始めます！
Mr. Koizumi to serve!
小泉先生 サービス！
調教する
I'll tame you.
レディー
Ready!
あの ご老体
本気でスマイルに勝つ気かな
Does the old geezer really think he can beat Smile?
He's got no chance.
無理 無理
昔は ならしたらしいけど—
I hear he was famous back in the day, but he's no match for Tsukimoto.
月本の敵じゃないよ
（小泉の声）
教えてあげるよ ミスター月本
Let me show you just how weak and frail your table tennis is, Mr. Tsukimoto.
君の卓球が
いかに軟弱で もろいかを
Hey!
That shouldn't've been a point.
外しましたよ　今 僕
But you returned, didn't you? Didn't you?!
（小泉）でも リターンしたもんね
したもんね したもんね！
（大田）ワンラブ ワンラブ
One-love! One-love!
That was pretty immature, Coach!
大人げないっすよ 先生！
He's good.
強い…
（小泉の声）
怒るか ミスター月本
Going to get mad, Mr. Tsukimoto?
No, you'll shrink from me.
いや 君は畏縮する
When an opponent challenges you aggressively...
闘志を むき出しに挑む相手に対し
おら！
There!
...you get scared.
（小泉の声）君は おびえる
Yeah!
しゃあ！
ほえるね じいさん
Listen to the old-timer roar.
よく知ってる
スマイルがイヤがること
He knows exactly what Smile hates.
I can see it.
（小泉の声）読めるよ
I can read you like a book.
君の考えてることが
手に取るように
You'll return a shot from this angle
with a flat hit straight down the line.
この角度の打球に対し—
君はストレートへ
ほぼフラットに返球する
ここだ！
There it is!
フウ…
（小泉の声）
そして 君の見切りは極めて早い
And you give up at the drop of a hat.
Accepting defeat with such good grace is naïve!
その潔さ—
甘い！
You cannot fly across an ocean on wings so thin.
その薄い羽では
海を渡ることはできない
Defeat and setbacks!
敗北と挫折
喪失と悲嘆
Loss and grief!
Amazing.
すげえ
（小泉の声）
孤立と混迷　苦悩と絶望
Isolation and turmoil.
Anguish and despair!
こりゃ 棺おけに
片足 突っ込んだ じいさんの…
This isn't how an old man with one foot in the grave...
Nihilism and ruin!
（小泉の声）虚無と堕落！
...is supposed to play.
（ペコ）プレーでねえぞ
（大田）ファイブラブ！
Five-love!
教えてあげるよ ミスター月本
I'll show you, Mr. Tsukimoto...
Eight-love!
エイトラブ！
君の甘さを！
...how naïve you are!
And the strong heart you'll need if you're to win!
勝つための強い心を！
It's safe and quiet here.
（スマイルの声）
ここは静かで安全な所だ
I really feel at ease.
とても落ち着くんだ
Someone's coming!
（スマイルの声）誰か来る
It's okay.
大丈夫　僕はここで平気なんだ
I'm fine here.
僕は ここにいたいんだ
This is where I want to be.
If I go out there, it'll happen again...
外へ出たら また…
また…
（大田）イレブンフォー！
ゲーム トゥ 小泉先生
Eleven-four!
Game to Mr. Koizumi.
Enter the hero.
（スマイルの声）
ヒーロー見参 ヒーロー見参
Enter the hero.
ヒーロー見参
He might actually beat him.
こりゃ ひょっとすると
ひょっとするぜ
（ペコの声）ヘヘッ 変わらねえな
スマイル お前は
You haven't changed one bit, Smile.
You're as naïve as ever.
甘さが抜けねえの
A drive down the middle is your weak point.
（小泉の声）弱点のミドル攻撃
とっさにフォアで打つか
バックで打つか迷うところ
You can't quickly decide whether to return it forehand or backhand.
But you always return the ball long with a backhand chop.
君は必ずバックカットで
ロングに打つと決めている
Utterly predictable.
実にワンパターン
Don't take me lightly!
ナメんな！
Does your benevolence run so deep, Mr. Tsukimoto?
君の慈悲は そこまで深いのかね？
ミスター月本
Are you prepared to become my dog?
私の犬になる覚悟は できたかね？
When I say "shake," you'll offer me your paw!
お手と言ったら お手をする
You'll spin around three times and bark!
３回 回ってワンと鳴く
I'll make you do it, Tsukimoto!
やってもらうぞ 月本！
I'll put a leash around your neck
and take you for walks every day!
私は君の首に縄を付けて
毎日 散歩する！
You are incredible!
君は素晴らしい
高齢化社会を支える
人間の かがみだ！
A shining example of the young supporting our aging society!
Why won't anybody leave me alone?
（スマイルの声）
どうして みんな僕に構うの？
Robot
Box
Cyborg
Where're your
batteries?
privates?
Rumba
何もしてないのに
怒ってもないのに
I don't do anything to them.
I don't get angry.
笑ってもいないのに
ただ いるだけなのに
I don't smile.
I'm just here.
I'm even breathing silently!
息も殺してる
言われたことだけ静かに
ロボットみたいにしてるのに
I quietly do as I'm told, like a robot.
ヒーロー見参
Enter the hero.
Smile, the hero
isn't coming
Enter the hero.
ヒーロー見参
Who's there?
誰？
Release
your
power
Your body
is iron
You don't feel
anything
No one can
hurt you
You are
a machine
Full throttle
Limits disengaged
Blow him away
ハンドオンテーブル！
Hand on table!
That costs you a point, Tsukimoto!
月本 それ失点！
Shut up.
うるさい
It's nothing to shout about.
大声 張り上げるほどのことじゃ
ないでしょ
I'd like you to be quiet too, Sir.
それから先生も黙ってください
気が散る以前に
不愉快なんですよ それ
It's more than distracting; it's annoying.
あっ これ
何か すごく反則の感じ！
Hey, that seriously feels against the rules!
Okay.
（小泉）はい
（ペコ）かっちょいい～
So cool.
（小泉）うう…
（スマイル）っしゃ！
イレブンシックス！
ゲーム トゥ 月本！
Eleven-six!
Game to Tsukimoto!
小泉老人 万事休すだな
Old Koizumi's finished.
He put up a good fight, though.
しかし この健闘は大したもんだよ
He's over 70, right?
（部員）
70過ぎだろ？ あのじいさん
もつれりゃ つれえさ
A close game's gotta be rough on him.
You've surprised me, Smile.
（ペコの声）驚いたぜ スマイル
お前 いつの間に
そんな打ち方…
When did you learn to play like that?
（オババ）無愛想なガキだね
挨拶もできないのかい
Not a very friendly kid.
Can't he even say "hello"?
（子供のペコ）
こいつ 笑わねえんだ
He never smiles.
Table tennis?
（子供のスマイル）卓球？
Gently, like you're holding an egg.
（子供のペコ）
卵 握るみてえによ そっとな
（スマイル）立ちませんか？ 先生
Would you please get up?
そうやって
いちいち間(ま)を空けられると—
It's extremely annoying how you pause after every point.
すごく不愉快です
There's no bed down there.
布団ないでしょ そこ
（小泉）
目がくらむ　５分くれないか？
I'm dizzy.
Could I have five minutes?
Ref! He wants to forfeit.
（スマイル）審判
彼 棄権するそうです
あー！ 今のウソ ウソ
取り消す
I was just kidding! I take it back!
ハハッ いいぞ ミスター月本
大変よい！
Good, Mr. Tsukimoto!
Excellent! Very good!
ベリーグーッド！
Koizumi doesn't look so good.
ヤバいぞ 小泉 あれ
He's lost his marbles.
完全に壊れとるぞ
Tsukimoto's heartless.
月本 非情だな
You get it, don't you, Mr. Tsukimoto?
（小泉の声）
分かるだろう？ ミスター月本
君が球を追うのではない
球が君を追うのだ
That you don't chase the ball.
The ball chases you.
You will become stronger.
君は強くなる
You can feel it, can't you, Mr. Tsukimoto?
感じるだろ？ ミスター月本
You feel the ball chase you!
球が君を追うのを
さあ 見せてくれ
Now, show me what you can do!
君の性能を！
抜くぞ！ 拾ってみせろ！
That'll go past you! Prove you can return it!
That's it, Tsukimoto!
そうだ　月本
The ball chases you!
球が君を追う
Can I be like you?
（スマイルの声）なれるかな
Think I can be like you, Peco?
（子供のスマイル）
僕もペコみたいになれるかな
ペコみたいになりたいんだ
I want to be like you, Peco.
Like you.
ペコみたいに
（部員）おーい
ひっくり返っちったよ 先生
Hey, the coach fell over!
（部員）頭 すごい音したぜ
His head went bang when it hit!
（部員）死んだ？
Is he dead?
保健室 行ってこい　１年！
First-years, go to the nurse's office!
おら！
Move it!
しかし 笑っとるぞ 小泉
But Koizumi's smiling.
ホントだ
You're right.
打ち所 悪かったか？
Did he land on a bad spot?
I'm going ahead, Peco.
僕 先に行くよ ペコ
What?
（スマイル）上がります
（大田）はあ？
I'm leaving.
Say what?! Don't be a jerk, Tsukimoto!
ふざけんな コラ 月本！
先生 卒倒してんだろ コラァ！
Teach just fainted!
シカトしてんのかよ！
Are you ignoring me?! Hey!
おい！ 待てよ 月本！
Wait! Tsukimoto!
A red sun stares at me
The world goes blurry when I yawn
My wishes fluctuate like a metronome
Everything tells me this is the end
I do have some dreams, you know
Sometimes we breathe
and just seem to inhale the smoke of someone
somewhere out of sight
Then all our great energy just seems to melt away
I don't understand this wonderland
I won't get wet even if it rains
This is a wonderland
Once I've made it through this long tunnel
I'm sure that someone will kiss me